hello world
{ "question":"What were the first words spoken on the moon?", 
"answers":[ "The pledge of allegiance", "The preamble of the constitution", "...one small step for a man, one giant leap for mankind", "Not known, the radio data failed"],
"explanation":""...one small step for a man, one giant leap for mankind" were the first words on the moon, spoken my Neil Armstrong. He claims he siad "...one small step for a man, AND ONE giant leap for mankind", but the radio did not pick up on it.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"What was the first Apollo Mission?", 
"answers":[ "Apollo 1", "Apollo 0", "Apollo 11", "Apollo 10"],
"explanation":"Apollo 1 was the first mission",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/index.html" },


{ "question":"When was the tragedy of the Apollo 1 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Jan. 27, 1967", "May 29, 1968", "Jul. 14, 1966", "Dec. 2, 1968"],
"explanation":"Jan. 27, 1967 was the day that a preflight test killed Virgil Grissom, Edward White, and Roger Chaffee",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo1.html" },


{ "question":"What is the name of the rocket primarily used in the Apollo missions?", 
"answers":[ "Atlas", "Falcon", "Saturn", "Delta"],
"explanation":"Rockets named Saturn were primarily used during the Apollo missions.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo1.html" },


{ "question":"What mission contained the first Saturn V launch?", 
"answers":[ "Apollo 11", "Apollo 4", "Apollo 1", "Apollo 10"],
"explanation":"Apollo 4 was the first to fly the Saturn V rocket",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo1.html" },


{ "question":"What year was the first Saturn rocket launched?", 
"answers":[ "1967", "1963", "1969", "1965"],
"explanation":"1967 was the first time the Saturn V rocket flew",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/audience/forstudents/5-8/features/nasa-knows/what-was-the-saturn-v-58.html" },


{ "question":"How heavy is the Saturn V rocket fully fueled?", 
"answers":[ "4.2 million kilograms", "8.1 million kilograms", ".9 million kilograms", "2.8 million kilograms"],
"explanation":"Fully fueled for liftoff, the Saturn V weighed 2.8 million kilograms (6.2 million pounds).",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/audience/forstudents/5-8/features/nasa-knows/what-was-the-saturn-v-58.html" },


{ "question":"How tall is the Saturn V rocket?", 
"answers":[ "314 meters", "111 meters", "161 meters", "72 meters"],
"explanation":"The Saturn V rocket was 111 meters tall",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/audience/forstudents/5-8/features/nasa-knows/what-was-the-saturn-v-58.html" },


{ "question":"How many elephants does the Saturn V rocket weigh when it is fully fueled?", 
"answers":[ "120", "1000", "650", "400"],
"explanation":"The Saturn V rocket weighed about 400 elephants when it was fueled for takeoff.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/audience/forstudents/5-8/features/nasa-knows/what-was-the-saturn-v-58.html" },


{ "question":"How many pounds of thrust did the Saturn V produce at launch?", 
"answers":[ "133.2 million newtons", "12.8 million newtons", "72.1 million newtons", "34.5 million newtons"],
"explanation":"The saturn V generated 34.5 million newtons(7.6 million pounds) of thrust at launch, which is more than 85 Hoover Dams.)",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/audience/forstudents/5-8/features/nasa-knows/what-was-the-saturn-v-58.html" },


{ "question":"When was the launch of Apollo 7?", 
"answers":[ "Jul. 21, 1968", "Oct. 11, 1968", "Aug. 20, 1969", "Feb. 2, 1966"],
"explanation":"Apollo 7 was launched on Oct. 11, 1968; 11:02:45 a.m. EST",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What launch complex did the Apollo 7 mission use?", 
"answers":[ "Launch Complex 37A", "Launch Complex 40", "Launch Complex 41", "Launch Complex 34"],
"explanation":"Apollo 7 was launched at Launch Complex 34",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What was the size of orbit of the Apollo 7 mission?", 
"answers":[ "334 miles", "141 miles", "212 miles", "180 miles"],
"explanation":"The orbit of Apollo 7 was 140 by 183 miles",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What was the point of keeping the S-IVB part of the craft in orbit with them in the Apollo 7 mission?", 
"answers":[ "It contained necessary food and supplies", "It was part of science equipment they needed", "So they could simulate docking", "They didn't want to, the jettison failed"],
"explanation":"They used the jettison part of the ship to simulate docking, a necessary part of the lunar mission",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"How did the engine perform on the Apollo 7 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Bad, but not bad enough that it caused issues.", "Nearly perfectly", "Incredibly poorly, and it was difficult to return from orbit", "Acceptable, but could have been better"],
"explanation":"There were eight nearly perfect firings out of eight attempts",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"How long did the Apollo 7 capsule stay in orbit?", 
"answers":[ "10.8 days", "5.9 days", "8.1 days", "3.2 days"],
"explanation":"Apollo 7 was in orbit for 10.8 days",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What was one of the medical issues the astronauts experienced on Apollo 7?", 
"answers":[ "A bad cold", "Dehydration", "Skin issues", "Eyesight issues from the sun"],
"explanation":"About 15 hours into the flight, Schirra developed a bad cold, and Cunningham and Eisele soon followed suit. A cold is uncomfortable enough on the ground, but in weightlessness it presents a different problem. Mucus accumulates, fills the nasal passages and does not drain from the head. The only relief is to blow hard, which is painful to the ear drums. So the crew of Apollo 7 whirled through space suffering from stopped-up ears and noses.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What was the landing spot of Apollo 7?", 
"answers":[ "12 degrees, 23 minutes north, and 12 degrees, 44 minutes west", "27 degrees, 32 minutes north, and 64 degrees, 4 minutes west", "31 degrees, 19 minutes north, and 44 degrees, 12 minutes west", "25 degrees, 40 minutes north, and 66 degrees, 52 minutes west"],
"explanation":"Apollo's flotation bags had their first try out when the spacecraft, considered a "lousy boat," splashed down in the Atlantic southeast of Bermuda, less than 2 kilometers from the planned impact point. The landing location was 27 degrees, 32 minutes north, and 64 degrees, 4 minutes west. The module turned upside down, but when inflated, the brightly colored bags flipped it upright.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"What time did the astronauts on Apollo 7 return to the ship?", 
"answers":[ "2:20 a.m. EDT", "3:36 p.m. EDT", "9:15 p.m. EDT", "8:20 a.m. EDT"],
"explanation":"The crew arrived at 8:20 a.m. EDT",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo7.html" },


{ "question":"Who was the Commander of the Apollo 8 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Neil Armstrong", "William A. Anders", "Frank Borman", "Edwin E. Aldrin Jr."],
"explanation":"The commander of the Apollo 8 mission was Frank Borman",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"When was the launch of Apollo 8?", 
"answers":[ "Oct. 3, 1968", "Jul. 14, 1968", "Mar. 28, 1967", "Dec. 21, 1968"],
"explanation":"Apollo 8 launched at Dec. 21, 1968; 7:51 a.m. EST",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"How long was the burn that sent Apollo 8 to the moon?", 
"answers":[ "Two-minutes, 45-seconds", "Five-minutes, 17-seconds", "Eight-minutes, 30-seconds", "Three-minutes, 22-seconds"],
"explanation":"The burn lasted Five-minues, 17 seconds",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"When did the loss of signal occur during the Apollo 8 mission when the austronauts went behind the moon?", 
"answers":[ "33 hours, 21 minutes, 19 seconds ", "81 hours, 36 minutes, 22 seconds ", "68 hours, 58 minutes, 45 seconds ", "40 hours, 9 minutes, 32 seconds "],
"explanation":"Loss of signal occurred at 68 hours, 58 minutes, 45 seconds when Apollo 8 passed behind the moon. At that moment, NASA's three astronauts became the first humans to see the moon's far side.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"How long did the first Lunar orbit insertion burn last on the Apollo 8 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Four minutes, two seconds", "Six minutes, eight-seconds", "Two-minute, 59-seconds", "Nine-minute, 30-seconds"],
"explanation":"The first lunar orbit insertion burn, at 69 hours, 8 minutes, 52 seconds, lasted four minutes, two seconds and reduced the spacecraft's 8,400 feet per second velocity by 2,994 feet per second",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"What was the size of the orbit around the moon on the Apollo 8 mission?", 
"answers":[ "12 miles", "112 miles", "44 miles", "70 miles"],
"explanation":"The orbit circularized at 70 miles by the second lunar orbit insertion burn of 135 feet per second, performed at the start of the third revolution, again on the back side of the moon",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"On Christmas eve, what message did the Apollo 8 astronauts brodcast home?", 
"answers":[ "A call to follow your country", "Merry Christmas, as well as verses from the book of Genesis in the Bible", "Endorsement of a political candidate", "A call to more science in the education system"],
"explanation":"During a telecast on Christmas Eve, the crew read verses from the first chapter of Genesis and wished viewers, "Good night, good luck, a Merry Christmas and God bless all of you - all of you on the good Earth."",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"What was the re-entry velocity of Apollo 8?", 
"answers":[ "62,471 mph", "13,942 mph", "24,696 mph", "44,326 mph"],
"explanation":"The re-entry velocity was 24,696 mph.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"What was the re-entry heat on the heatsheild of Apollo 8", 
"answers":[ "8,000 degrees F", "15,000 degrees F", "2,000 degrees F", "5,000 degrees F"],
"explanation":"The heatshield withstood teampatures of 5,000 degrees F",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"What time did the Apollo 8 crew get to the ship?", 
"answers":[ "7:41 p.m. EST", "1:12 a.m. EST", "12:20 p.m. EST", "3:16 p.m. EST"],
"explanation":"The Apollo 8 crew reached the recovery ship at 12:20 p.m. EST.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"How long did the Apollo 8 crew have to wait in the command module in the ocean?", 
"answers":[ "50 minutes", "4 minutes", "2 hours", "38 minutes"],
"explanation":" According to prior planning, helicopters and aircraft hovered over the spacecraft, and pararescue personnel were not deployed until local sunrise, 50 minutes after splashdown.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo8.html" },


{ "question":"Who was the commander of Apollo 9?", 
"answers":[ "David R. Scott", "Alan L. Bean", "James A. McDivitt", "Neil Armstrong"],
"explanation":"James A. McDivitt was the commander of the Apollo 9 mission.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"When did Apollo 9 launch?", 
"answers":[ "Oct. 8, 1968", "Jan. 17, 1970", "March 3, 1969", "May 21, 1968"],
"explanation":"Apollo 9 launched on March 3, 1969",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"What was the orbit of Apollo 9 after it circulized?", 
"answers":[ "123 by 127 miles", "142 by 140 miles", "112 by 113 miles", "155 by 160 miles"],
"explanation":"On the first day, and after orbit injection of the combined S-IVB stage and its SLA-LM-CSM payload, venting of the S-IVB propellant tanks changed the orbit to 123 by 127 miles",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"What was one of the main goals of the Apollo 9 testing wise?", 
"answers":[ "Docking", "Orbits", "Crew stability", "Rocket launching"],
"explanation":"NASA wanted to make sure that docking was going too work",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"What was one of the reasons the orbit of Apollo 9 was expanded?", 
"answers":[ "Overshooting the rocket launch", "Bad interpretation of measurements", "Engine misfire", "Test firing the lunar module"],
"explanation":"This included a 367-second firing of the LM descent engine to simulate the throttle pattern to be used during a lunar landing mission. McDivitt controlled the final 59 seconds, varying the thrust from 10 to 40 percent and shutting it off manually. This was the first crewed throttling of an engine in space and increased the spacecraft's orbit to 130 by 300 miles.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"Why was the two-hour EVA cancelled on the Apollo 9 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Saftey risks", "Nasusa", "Radio connection issues", "The door failed"],
"explanation":"Because of nausea, Schweickart's scheduled two-hour EVA to simulate external transfer rescue techniques was canceled. Instead, he climbed out of the LM porch for a 37.5 minute EVA, testing the EVA mobility unit, including the portable life support system backpack.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"Why was the Apollo 9 mission extended by one day?", 
"answers":[ "Needed more time for testing", "Ship was having issues during entry and they had to cancel", "Rough seas in the primary landing location", "The ship that was supposed to pick them up was down for maintenance"],
"explanation":"On March 13, the tenth day, re-entry was extended by one revolution because of heavy seas in the primary recovery area.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo9.html" },


{ "question":"How close did the new lunar module get to landing on the Apollo 10 mission?", 
"answers":[ "15 miles", "70 miles", "9 miles", "Less that 1 mile"],
"explanation":"The lunar module had a descent to about nine miles off the moon's surface",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"What was the main purpose of Apollo 10", 
"answers":[ "See if the Saturn V rocket could lift that much weight", "Practice everything except the landing", "Refine radio transmissions", "Unknown, it has been clasified"],
"explanation":"The Apollo 10 mission encompassed all aspects of an actual crewed lunar landing, except the landing.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"Whats the velocity of Apollo 10 on the way to the moon?", 
"answers":[ "42,522 feet per second", "51,942 feet per second", "36,651 feet per second", "62,152 feet per second"],
"explanation":"One-and-a-half orbits later, translunar injection occurred. The S-IVB fired to increase velocity from 25,593 to 36,651 feet per second.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"Whats the velocity of Apollo 10 on the way to the moon?", 
"answers":[ "62,152 feet per second", "51,942 feet per second", "42,522 feet per second", "36,651 feet per second"],
"explanation":"The Apollo 10 crew members were Commander Thomas Stafford, Command Module Pilot John Young and Lunar Module Pilot Eugene Cernan.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"Who was the commander of Apollo 10?", 
"answers":[ "John Young", "George Washington", "Thomas Stafford", "Neil Armstrong"],
"explanation":"The Apollo 10 crew members were Commander Thomas Stafford, Command Module Pilot John Young and Lunar Module Pilot Eugene Cernan.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"Which Apollo mission had the first color braodcast?", 
"answers":[ "Apollo 9", "Apollo 8", "Apollo 14", "Apollo 10"],
"explanation":"The first live color TV transmissions to Earth began three hours after launch when Apollo 10 was 3,570 miles from Earth and concluded when the spacecraft was 9,428 miles away.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"How big was the lunar orbit on Apollo 10?", 
"answers":[ "32 miles", "69 miles", "256 miles", "112 miles"],
"explanation":"The lunar orbit of Apollo 10 was approximately 69 miles.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"What was the Lunar orbit of the Apollo 10 lunar module", 
"answers":[ "17 by 142.1 miles.", "9.7 by 70.5 miles.", "14.2 by 65.5 miles", "22.1 by 59.9 miles"],
"explanation":"To achieve a simulation of the future Apollo 11 landing, the LM descent engine fired for 27.4 seconds, with 10 percent thrust for the first 15 seconds and 40 percent thrust for the rest. This brought the LM to a new orbit of 9.7 by 70.5 miles.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo10.html" },


{ "question":"What was the primary mission of the Apollo 11 mission?", 
"answers":[ "Do a test run before the real landing", "Perform a crewed lunar landing and return to Earth.", "Rescue crew left on Apollo 10", "Practice the Saturn V launch"],
"explanation":"The primary objective of Apollo 11 was to complete a national goal set by President John F. Kennedy on May 25, 1961: perform a crewed lunar landing and return to Earth.",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"Approximately how many people watched the moon landing?", 
"answers":[ "325 million", "100 million", "1 billion", "530 million"],
"explanation":"Apollo 11 launched from Cape Kennedy on July 16, 1969",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"When did Apollo 11 launch?", 
"answers":[ "Feb. 22, 1969", "July 16, 1969", "Oct. 10, 1969", "July 8, 1969"],
"explanation":"Apollo 11 launched from Cape Kennedy on July 16, 1969",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"Who was the commander of Apollo 11?", 
"answers":[ "Michael Collins", "Edwin "Buzz" Aldrin", "Neil Armstrong", "James A. McDivitt"],
"explanation":"The commander of Apollo 11 was Neil Armstrong",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"When did Apollo 11 land on the moon?", 
"answers":[ "July 4, 1969", "July 20, 1969", "Feb 2, 12968", "June 14, 1970"],
"explanation":"Apollo 11 landed on the moon on July 20, 1969",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


{ "question":"What was the nickname of the lunar module on Apollo 11?", 
"answers":[ "Dragon", "Foxcat", "Eagle", "Falcon"],
"explanation":"Apollo 11 landed on the moon on July 20, 1969",
"source":"https://www.nasa.gov/mission_pages/apollo/missions/apollo11.html" },


